{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The workers are hell bent at getting what is due to them.", "opta": "hell bent on getting", "optb": "hell bent for getting", "optc": "hell bent upon getting", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When it was feared that the serfs might go too far and gain their freedom from serfdom, the protestant leaders joined the princes at crushing them.", "opta": "into crushing", "optb": "in crushing", "optc": "without crushing", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the room had been brighter, I would have been able to read for a while before bed time.", "opta": "If the room was brighter", "optb": "If the room are brighter", "optc": "Had the room been brighter", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The record for the biggest tiger hunt has not been met since 1911 when Lord Hardinge. then Viceroy of India, shot a tiger than measured 11 feet and 6 inches.", "opta": "improved", "optb": "broken", "optc": "bettered", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "his powerful desire brought about his downfall.", "opta": "His intense desire", "optb": "His desire for power", "optc": "His fatal desire", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Will you kindly open the knot?", "opta": "untie", "optb": "break", "optc": "loose", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He sent a word to me that he would be coming late.", "opta": "sent word", "optb": "had sent a word", "optc": "sent words", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "John had told me that he hasn't done it yet.", "opta": "told", "optb": "tells", "optc": "was telling", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If he had time he will call you.", "opta": "would have", "optb": "would have had", "optc": "has", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Will you lend me few rupees in this hour of need?", "opta": "lend me any rupees", "optb": "borrow me a few rupees", "optc": "lend me a few rupees", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During his long discourse, he did not touch that point.", "opta": "touch upon", "optb": "touch on", "optc": "touch of", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He found a wooden broken chair in the room.", "opta": "wooden and broken chair", "optb": "broken wooden chair", "optc": "broken and wooden chair", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He could not look anything in the dark room.", "opta": "look at", "optb": "see", "optc": "see through", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The greatest thing in style is to have a use of metaphor.", "opta": "knowledge", "optb": "command", "optc": "need", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "While crossing the highway a five year old child was knocked out by a passing car.", "opta": "away", "optb": "up", "optc": "down", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "hoping not to be disturbed, I sat down in my easy chair to read the book. I won as a prize.", "opta": "I had won as a prize", "optb": "I have won as prize", "optc": "I had to win as a prize", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "More than one person was killed in accident.", "opta": "were killed", "optb": "are killed", "optc": "have been killed", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The expression more than one + noun, though plural in sense, is followed by a singular verb.\nExample: More than one person has died in the accident.\nExplanation provided by: Samy Kumar. Updated on 4th Aug 2018."}, {"question": "No one could explain how a calm and balanced person like him could penetrate such a mindless act on his friends.", "opta": "perpetuate", "optb": "perpetrate", "optc": "precipitate", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Five years ago today, I am sitting in a small Japanese car, driving across Poland towards Berlin.", "opta": "was sitting", "optb": "sat", "optc": "have been sitting", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I took the cycle which he bought yesterday.", "opta": "that he bought yesterday", "optb": "that which he had bought yesterday", "optc": "that he had bought yesterday", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Please make it a point to send you letter at my address.", "opta": "on my address", "optb": "to my address", "optc": "in my address", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you are living near a market place you should be ready to bear the disturbances caused by traffic.", "opta": "to bear upon", "optb": "to bear with", "optc": "to bear away", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I hope you won't object to me watching while you work.", "opta": "against me watching", "optb": "me to watch", "optc": "to my watching", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You cannot forbid him leaving.", "opta": "he leaving", "optb": "his leaving", "optc": "him to leave", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You have come here with a view to insult me.", "opta": "to insulting me", "optb": "of insulting me", "optc": "for insulting me", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "20 kms are not a great distance in these days of fast moving vehicles.", "opta": "is not a great distance", "optb": "is no distance", "optc": "aren't a great distance", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The more they earn, more they spend.", "opta": "More they earn, more they spend", "optb": "More they earn, the more they spend", "optc": "The more they earn, the more they spend", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It became clear that the strangers were heading into a serious disaster.", "opta": "along", "optb": "towards", "optc": "for", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dissidents hold a great problem in every political party.", "opta": "cause", "optb": "give", "optc": "pose", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I would have waited for you at the station if I knew that you would come.", "opta": "had known", "optb": "was knowing", "optc": "have known", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They are social insects, living in communities, regulated by definite laws, each member of society bearing well-defined and separate part in the work of a colony.", "opta": "who are living in communities", "optb": "living among a community", "optc": "who lives with a community", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Practically every part of the banana tree is used by man.", "opta": "each part", "optb": "any part", "optc": "most part", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "My opinion for  the film is that it will bag the national ward.", "opta": "opinion to", "optb": "opinion about", "optc": "opinion on", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The end of the examinations is (an) oppurtunity for celebrating.", "opta": "chance", "optb": "moment", "optc": "occasion", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We were not the wiser for all this effort to explain the case to us.", "opta": "none", "optb": "neither", "optc": "nevertheless", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Whenever my students come across new words, I ask them to look for them in the dictionary.", "opta": "to look it up", "optb": "to look them up", "optc": "to look at them", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We look forward to hear from you.", "opta": "hearing", "optb": "have heard", "optc": "listen", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It was indeed a shock for her, but she has later recovered from it.", "opta": "since", "optb": "then", "optc": "afterwards", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Realising is the significance of technical education for developing country, the government laid aside a large sum on it during the last plan-period.", "opta": "laid up", "optb": "set aside", "optc": "laid out", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you are not clear about the meaning of a word, it is wise to look to a dictionary.", "opta": "look for", "optb": "look at", "optc": "look up", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You are warned against committing the same mistake again.", "opta": "to commit", "optb": "for committing", "optc": "against to commit", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "No sooner he had returned home then his mother felt happy.", "opta": "had he returned home when", "optb": "he had returned home than", "optc": "did he return home than", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He should move on to the next point, and not harp one sting only.", "opta": "harp on string only", "optb": "harp only one string", "optc": "harp upon one string only", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Either he or I am going.", "opta": "he or I are going", "optb": "he is going or I am", "optc": "I or he is going", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I hope you vividly remember the premier of the film when I, my wife and you were present in the hall.", "opta": "my wife, I and you", "optb": "you, I and my wife", "optc": "my wife, you and I", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To get one's name in the Rowland Ward's book of hunting records was the hot ambition of every serious hunter.", "opta": "extreme", "optb": "burning", "optc": "high", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Taxpayers are to be conscious of their privileges.", "opta": "have to", "optb": "need", "optc": "ought to", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As she was suffering from high fever, she could not face the examination.", "opta": "bear", "optb": "suffer", "optc": "take", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The demonstration passed off peacefully.", "opta": "passed out", "optb": "passed away", "optc": "passed on", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Every time I go in a lift to my sixth floor apartment, I remember the calm and serenity of my ancestral home in the village.", "opta": "move in a lift", "optb": "ascend in a lift", "optc": "take a lift", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In fact, if it hadn't been for his invaluable advice on so many occasions I wouldn't have achieved anything in life.", "opta": "remarkable advice", "optb": "valuable advices", "optc": "priceless suggestion", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mr. Smith arrived at India in June last year.", "opta": "to", "optb": "by", "optc": "in", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "But in all these cases conversion from scale have well-formulated.", "opta": "can be well-formulated", "optb": "are well-formulated", "optc": "well-formulated", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a thundering roar the huge rocket soared up from the launching pad.", "opta": "flew up", "optb": "went upwards", "optc": "took off", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "There is dearth of woman doctor in our state. We shall have to recruit some from the other states.", "opta": "women doctor", "optb": "woman doctors", "optc": "women doctors", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you cross the line you will be disqualified.", "opta": "cross upon the line", "optb": "cross on the line", "optc": "cross out the line", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why the dinosaurs died out is not known.", "opta": "it is not known", "optb": "the reason is not known", "optc": "that is not known", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "His father won't be able to leave for Varnasi until they have arrived.", "opta": "until they arrive", "optb": "until they will have arrived", "optc": "until they will arrive", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I will not go to school, if it shall rain tomorrow.", "opta": "it would rain tomorrow", "optb": "it will rain tomorrow", "optc": "it rains tomorrow", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If I stood alone in defence of truth, and the whole world is banded against me and against truth. I would fight them all.", "opta": "will be banded", "optb": "were banded", "optc": "banded", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He has not and can never be in the good books of his employer because he lacks honesty.", "opta": "has not and cannot be", "optb": "has not and can never been", "optc": "has not been and can never be", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the examinations were over Anil and me went to our native town.", "opta": "me and Anil", "optb": "Anil and I", "optc": "I and Anil", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Our office clock is not so correct as it should be it is usually five minutes fast.", "opta": "right", "optb": "regular", "optc": "accurate", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cloud of misfortunes appears to have blown out.", "opta": "over", "optb": "up", "optc": "away", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "While we would like that all Indian Children to go to school, we need to ponder why they do not.", "opta": "that all the Indian children", "optb": "if all the children of India", "optc": "all Indian children", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In India today many of our intellectuals still talk in terms of the French Revolution and the Rights of Man, not appreciating that much has happened since then.", "opta": "much has been happening", "optb": "much had happened", "optc": "much might happen", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I shall be grateful to you if you are of help to me now.", "opta": "help", "optb": "would help", "optc": "helped", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic of Berlin wall already had been undermined but when the news came through that the wall itself had been opened I jumped into a car.", "opta": "had been undetermined already", "optb": "had already been undetermined", "optc": "had been already undetermined", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Other countries have eradicated this disease ten years ago.", "opta": "eradicated", "optb": "had eradicated", "optc": "did eradicated", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Young men and women should get habituated to reading and writing about current affairs.", "opta": "used", "optb": "prepared", "optc": "trained", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The poor villagers have waited in the bitter cold for more than 4 hours now.", "opta": "have been waiting", "optb": "had waited", "optc": "has been waiting", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The old man felled some trees in the garden with hardly no effort at all.", "opta": "hard effort", "optb": "hardly any effort", "optc": "a hardly any effort", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The company goes to great length to ensure that employees can be comfortable in their work environment.", "opta": "are comfortable", "optb": "will be comfortable", "optc": "should be comfortable", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I want you to clearly understand that excuses won't do", "opta": "you clearly to understand", "optb": "you to understand clearly", "optc": "to clearly understand you", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He was fined for careless driving.", "opta": "got fined", "optb": "fined", "optc": "was to be fined", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Although India is still by far a poor country, it can become rich if its natural and human resources are fully utilised.", "opta": "few and far between", "optb": "by and large", "optc": "by and by", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reason why he wrote the letter was because he could not contact him over the phone.", "opta": "why he wrote the letter was since", "optb": "for which he wrote the letter because", "optc": "why he wrote the letter was that", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As he is past his teens now, he can look for himself.", "opta": "after", "optb": "to", "optc": "around", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "There is no more room for you in this compartment.", "opta": "there is no more seat", "optb": "there is no more space", "optc": "there is no more accommodation", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most donors would seriously protest any effort to extrapolate from such limited data.", "opta": "protest against", "optb": "protest at", "optc": "protest to", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "She says she's already paid me back, but I can't remember, so I 'll have to take her word.", "opta": "to take her word true", "optb": "to take her at her word", "optc": "to take her word for it", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you had attended the meeting, you would have benefited a great deal.", "opta": "could benefit", "optb": "would benefit", "optc": "benefited", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This matter admits of no excuse.", "opta": "admits to", "optb": "admits from", "optc": "admits", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If he would have tried he would have succeeded.", "opta": "is tried", "optb": "was tried", "optc": "had tried", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It will be no good trying to find an excuse next time.", "opta": "to try to find", "optb": "to try finding", "optc": "trying finding", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Please remind me of posting these letters to my relatives.", "opta": "by posting", "optb": "to post", "optc": "for posting", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Not a word they spoke to the unfortunate wife about it", "opta": "did they speak", "optb": "they will speak", "optc": "they had spoken", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Not long back, in Japan, a mysterious nerve gas affected a large number of people.", "opta": "effected", "optb": "infected", "optc": "infested", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We had nothing to eat since 8'o clock, this morning.", "opta": "have had nothing", "optb": "has had nothing", "optc": "did have nothing", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We did not see this movie yet.", "opta": "have seen", "optb": "have not seen", "optc": "have seen", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "My friend was in hospital for a week after an accident.", "opta": "through", "optb": "following", "optc": "for", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All, but her,  had made an attempt.", "opta": "All, but she,", "optb": "All, but herself,", "optc": "All, but her,", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Whatever to our other problems. we have no shortcoming to cheap labour in India.", "opta": "default", "optb": "deficit", "optc": "scarcity", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I have lived in Delhi since I was four.", "opta": "am living", "optb": "lived", "optc": "had lived", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This telephone number is not existing.", "opta": "has not existed", "optb": "does not exist", "optc": "has not been existing", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I shall not go untill I am invited.", "opta": "till I am invited", "optb": "Unless I am invited", "optc": "if not I am invited", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He died in the year 1960 at 11pm on 14 July.", "opta": "on 14 July in the year 1960 at 11pm", "optb": "in the year 1960 on 14 July at 11pm", "optc": "at 11pm on 14 July in the year 1960", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Due to these reason we are all in favour of universal compulsory education.", "opta": "Out of these reasons", "optb": "For these reasons", "optc": "By these reasons", "optd": "No improvement", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}